Sharon Watkins

New Albany, PA 18833 | 570-637-8765 | swatkins876@gmail.com Github sedx876 | Blog | LinkedIn

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Ruby on Rails and JavaScript based programming and a background in healthcare and media. Possesses strong skills in organization, mediation and project management that help companies maintain and build existing projects. Mother who is successfully managing and educating 4 children at home during the pandemic.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, OOP, SQL, Javascript, React, Redux, Node

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

D3PlayrCompanion - Github | Demo

An app for players of Diablo 3 to help keep track of characters that the user has built in-game with a digital card. Eliminates manual means of tracking character and game changes.

- Implemented Bcrypt Gem and User Sessions to store encrypted user information.
- Employed Ruby on Rails as an API to handle backend information.
- Used React/Redux to present information to a user.
- Incorporated Redux-Thunk and Rack-CORS to bring together backend and frontend.

MeetrReadr - Github | Demo

App for readers based on GoodReads to discover books and other avid readers to help foster conversations and ideas.

- Utilized Github OAuth as an alternative login option.
- Exercised Ruby on Rails for both backend and frontend.
- Applied MVC pattern to handle logic and UI.
- Employed paperclip gem so users can upload images of books.

Strain Domain - Github | Demo

App for medical marijuana patients to track and journal what works and what doesn't work for their specific diagnosis.

- Employed Ruby on Rails as an API to handle backend information.
- Used Object Oriented Vanilla JavaScript for client-side presentation and DOM manipulation.
- Utilized SQLite relational DB to persist and maintain data.
- Incorporated beta-testers to track bugs and gage user experience.

EXPERIENCE

Stay at Home Mother Mother

New Albany, PA 06/2016 - Present

- Providing a safe and nurturing environment for continuing education.
- Mediating and problem solving for disputes and conflicts that arise.
- Organizing and creating a routine for others to increase and maintain consistent productivity.
- Creating and executing various activities to help maintain positive mental and physical health.

GhostWalk Studios, LLC

Cincinnati, OH

Administrative Assistant// Art Department Assistant with an iMDB film credit

01/2009 - 06/2016

- Managed social media accounts to build online presence and branding.
- Utilized Photoshop to create graphics and merchandise.
- Created a quarterly digital magazine to showcase the company and its productions.
- Managed and organized jobs for others to increase productivity and results.
- Researched and presented various ideas and concepts to find a solution for specific problems.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Online

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

09/2019 - 10/2020

Mansfield University
Nursing
Mansfield, PA
08/ 2002